medicinenet.com 2000-12-07

# MedicineNet.com - Medical References - Privacy Policy

**MedicineNet.com Privacy and Security Policy**

At MedicineNet.com your privacy is important to us. We will never willfully disclose personally identifiable information about our customers to any third party without prior consent.

**TRUSTe Certification**[](https://www.truste.org/validate/3900)

This confirms that MedicineNet.com is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for www.medicinenet.com's entire web site, including sites powered by MedicineNet.com; www.MedTerms.com, www.AboutArthritis.com, www.AboutDigestion.com, www.FocusOnCholesterol.com.

TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, this web site has agreed to notify you of: 

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personally identification is collected from you through the web site,
  2. The organization collecting the information,
  3. How the information is used,
  4. With whom the information may be shared,
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information,
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under MedicineNet.com control,
  7. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact the MedicineNet.com Smart Service Team by e-mail at [ smartservice@medicinenet.com](mailto:smartservice@medicinenet.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe <http://www.truste.org/watchdog.html>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns.

**Table of Contents**

Our Philosophy   
Information Collection and Use  
Disclosure of the Information   
Opt-out Features   
Changing Your Personal Information   
Links on our Site  
Advertising on our Site  
Security Policy  
Notification of Changes

**Our Philosophy**     Back to Top

MedicineNet.com has developed this privacy policy to ensure our firm commitment to your privacy and security. We understand as a provider of medical information the nature of each transaction is extremely sensitive. So we give you the power to decide how much information you provide combined with the ability to view or update your personally identifiable information at any time. In addition, you control what information you receive from MedicineNet.com--we will never contact you without prior consent.

**Information Collection and Use**     Back to Top

MedicineNet.com is the sole owner of all information collected on our network of sites. We do not sell or rent any personally identifiable information about you to any third party. We may share the summary-not individual-reports we develop about our customers, in accordance with this Privacy Statement.  An example of this information might be "10,000 people clicked on advertisement 'A' today and of those people, 40% previously indicated an interest in arthritis." These reports may be shared with our partners or advertisers, however we will never disclose personally identifiable statistics.

**My Account Registration**  
We need your e-mail address and a password of your choosing, to set-up and login to your account. If you choose to register for a Newsletter or Forum Update alert, establishing an account is required. You may at any time opt-out of receiving special information through the Newsletter and Forum Update Registration area of My Account. 

**Traffic Patterns**  
We collect traffic patterns and site usage information throughout our site. As part of this we collect the URL you came from in entering our site, what browser you are using, your IP address, and the URL you go to from our site if it is a link or advertiser on our site. In addition, we use Cookies to assign a unique, random number to identify your computer. Cookies, by themselves, cannot identify you personally or any other individual using your computer. Cookies allow us to keep track of shopping carts, login information (for increased security), and site traffic patterns and usage.

**E-mail a Friend  
**If you choose to use the E-mail a Friend feature, we ask for your friend's E-mail address to deliver the information. This will be a one-time correspondence from MedicineNet.com.

**Viewer Suggestions  
**If you choose to submit a Viewer Suggestion to MedicineNet.com, we require your first name while your e-mail address and last name are optional. You may receive a one-time communication from MedicineNet.com in response to your suggestion. You can indicate through your comment if you would rather not hear from us. 

**Surveys and Polls**  
Periodically, we may also ask for other demographic information as part of a survey or poll. It is not mandatory for you to answer these questions. If you decide to answer these questions, your individual answers will remain confidential. We will only use survey information in the aggregate to study statistical results. Examples of such information are as follows; age, gender, occupation, marital status, family size, areas of interest, or medical related questions.

**Discussion Boards**  
If you choose to participate in a discussion (message board or chat), we need your name, e-mail address and a password of your choosing, to establish an account to allow access to discussions. Any personally identifiable information you disclose through the use of discussions (message boards or chats) is voluntary and will be used in accordance with MedicineNet.com's Discussion Rules. MedicineNet.com is not liable for any personally identifiable information you choose to disclose as part of a discussion (message boards or chats). 

**Featured Products** _  
_ If you choose to purchase Featured Products through MedicineNet.com, we collect additional information. We need your full name, e-mail address, credit card number and expiration date, phone number, billing address and shipping address if different from your billing address. This personally identifiable information will be utilized only to fulfill your product purchase. 

**Shopping**  
You may choose to shop through our partner Walsh Distribution and their healthcareamerica.com (HCA) program. Shopping transactions occur through our partners website and are independent of MedicineNet.com. All information collected through HCA is maintained as a separate account on their web server and is protected through their Privacy and Security Policy.

HCA collects the following information: username, e-mail address, a password of your choosing, and a password hint to establish and login to your shopping account; full name, address, and e-mail address for shipping of products and credit card information, full name, address and phone number for billing.

**Membership Sign-up**  
In addition to the above information, if you choose to become a member of MedicineNet.com we collect additional information. We need your e-mail address, a password of your choosing, to set-up and login to your membership account and access member benefits. To purchase a membership, we also need to know your full name, credit card number and expiration date, phone number, billing address and the following demographic information; gender, age, marital status, number of children, occupation and type of industry. This personally identifiable information will be utilized only to fulfill your membership agreement.

**Disclosure of your Information**     Back to Top

We do not sell or rent any personally identifiable information about you to any third party. We may share non-personal, aggregate information regarding customer demographics, traffic patterns, sales, and site usage with our partners, advertisers or sponsors. We will never willfully disclose personally identifiable information about our customers to any third party without prior consent. 

We are required to share certain information with our partners, in accordance with our Security Policy, in order to complete Membership sign-up and Featured Products purchases. To process your credit card and reduce fraud we must share your name, billing address, phone number, and credit card information with CyberSource® and your name, shipping address and purchased items to our shipping and fulfillment partners. Certain information will never be disclosed, including your password and credit card. 

In special cases MedicineNet.com may believe it is necessary to disclose personally identifiable information in order to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating or causing injury to or interference with MedicineNet.com's rights or property, other users, or any other party that could be harmed by such activities. We may also disclose or access personally identifiable information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

**Opt-out Features**

Back to Top

MedicineNet.com believes that you should control your healthcare decisions, including what information you receive from us. The choices are yours to make. You can tell us if you don't want to receive the Newsletters and e-mail Update Alerts, through My Account, unsubscribe from any newsletter or update alert you receive, or by e-mail, phone, or mail request.

**Changing Your Personal Information**     Back to Top

You may correct and update your personal information at any time. All you have to do is Login to My Account and edit the information. You may also notify us via e-mail, phone, or mail request to assist you in making these changes. If you participate in discussions (message boards or chats), you can update your personal information at any time by choosing edit profile once in the discussion environment.

To change personal information entered while shopping with our partner, you must Login through HCA's account on their site. You can access HCA directly from MedicineNet.com's Account Menu or through the Shopping link in the Template.

**Your Consent**     Back to Top

By using the MedicineNet.com web site, those sites powered by MedicineNet.com, and the services available to you on our sites, you consent to the collection and use of your information as described above. If we change our privacy policy, we will immediately post the changes on this page so that you are always aware of our policies.

**Links on our Site**     Back to Top

MedicineNet.com has provided links to various sites that we believe provide valuable information to you, our viewer. However, we are not responsible for the privacy practices, content, or actions of such web sites.

**Advertising on our Site**     Back to Top

The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to you by DoubleClick's Sonar Network, our Web advertising partner. Our third-party advertising company also separately places or recognizes a cookie file on your browser in the course of delivering advertisements to this Site. Information about your visit to this site (but not your name, address, or other personally identifiable information) is used to serve ads to you on this site. This information is not collected by Sonar and DoubleClick for profiling. For more information about Sonar, cookies, and your right to "opt-out", please click [here](http://www.sonar.com/content/privacy.htm). 

**Security Policy**     Back to Top

How We Protect Your Personal Information

We utilize all appropriate security and encryption methods provided by VeriSign™ and CyberSource®.  MedicineNet.com uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, a security standard supported by Microsoft Internet Explorer (3.0 and higher) and Netscape Navigator (2.0 and higher), whenever sensitive information is transmitted between your browser and our network and when we transmit between our network and CyberSource®. Furthermore, your credit card and other personal information will be (a) encrypted (using 128-bit encryption) when transmitted through any part of our computer network, (b) secured behind a computer firewall when retained in our electronic files and (c) protected by password thereby accessible only by entering your user name and password. 

Credit Card Fraud Protection

Under the Fair Credit Billing Act, your credit card provider cannot hold you liable for more than $50.00 of fraudulent charges. If your credit card provider does hold you liable for any of this $50.00 amount, MedicineNet.com will cover your entire liability up to the full $50.00. MedicineNet.com will only cover this liability if the unauthorized use of your credit card resulted through no fault of your own and only for purchases made at MedicineNet.com while using our secure server. In the event of an unauthorized use of your credit card, you must notify your credit card provider in accordance with its reporting rules and procedures. 

**Notification of Changes**

We will notify you directly if there is a major change in our privacy practices. We will take reasonable measures to obtain written or active e-mail consent from you if MedicineNet.com is going to be using the information collected from you in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection. In addition, all changes in our privacy statement will be posted 30 days in advance.

Back to Top
